Nodoka
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Nodoka
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
Nodoka
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Kaede-chan made it to school at night!
Today
I heard. Sakuta told me over the phone last night.
He said she'll try school during the day today.
Episode 13: The Dawn After an Endless Night
(麻衣)まだ家にいる時間よね｡
They should still be at home, right?
Sakuta
Home
Calling
[℡]どうした？ 咲太｡
What's the matter, Sakuta?
(咲太)かえでの記憶が
戻ったみたい｡
Kaede's memories seem to have returned.
[℡]本当か…｡
僕が間違えるわけないし｡
Really?
There's no way I'd ever get it wrong.
[℡]そうだな…｡
Guess not.
I'm thinking of getting her checked
at the hospital. Can you come?
今から 病院で診てもらおうと
思うけど 来られる？
I'll be there.
[℡]わかった｡
記憶を失っていた間のことは
何も覚えていないようですね｡
She doesn't seem to remember anything
that happened during her amnesic period.
今は まだ状況を
理解しきれていないようですが
She probably hasn't fully
understood her situation yet,
しばらくすると
記憶の空白部分に
but the gap in her memory
will eventually destabilize her.
戸惑うようになってくると
思います｡
落ち着くまで入院して
様子を見るのがいいでしょう｡
We should admit and monitor her
until it blows over.
よろしくお願いします｡
Please take care of her.
I don't think there's anything
wrong with me, y'know.
(花楓)私 どこも
悪くないと思うんだけどな｡
本当に花楓なんだな？
Kaede, it's really you...
うっ…｡
お父さん どうしたの？
Dad? What's wrong?
違う これは…｡
Oh no... This is...
なんか 私が恥ずかしいよ｡
そうだな｡
Uh, why're you making this awkward?
Right.
泣くことないじゃん 別に｡
What's there to even cry about?
どこ行くの？
ちょっとﾄｲﾚ｡
Where're you going?
Gotta hit the restroom.
うわぁ～!!
うわぁ!!
うわぁ…｡
What happened to going to see the pandas again?
またﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞ
見に行くんじゃなかったのかよ｡
年間ﾊﾟｽのもととるって
言ったじゃないかよ｡
Didn't you say you'd use the yearly pass
for its money's worth?
明日には学校にも行けそう…
行けそうだって…｡
You said you thought you could go...
to school tomorrow...
言ってたんだよ かえでは！
Kaede said that, damn it!
ざけんなよ… ざけんなって｡
No way.
This can't be happening!
Screw you! What is this?
ざけんな！ なんだよ これ
なんなんだよ！
What's going on?!
You'll be all right, Sakuta-kun.
(翔子)咲太くんは大丈夫です｡
翔子さん…｡
Shouko-san?
Yes. It's your Shouko-san.
はい 翔子さんです｡
私が来たから もう大丈夫です｡
Now that I'm here, you'll be all right.
I'm coming in.
(翔子)開けますよ
着替え中でも事故ですからね｡
If you're changing, it wasn't on purpose, okay?
It'll be a bit longer until the bath's ready.
お風呂が沸くまで
まだ少しかかります｡
そのままじゃ
風邪をひいてしまいますよ｡
Dry up before you catch a cold.
はい 万歳してください｡
Okay, raise your arms for me.
大丈夫 血は
止まってるみたいですね｡
It's all right. The bleeding has stopped.
ｽﾞﾎﾞﾝとﾊﾟﾝﾂも 私が脱がします？
自分で脱ぎます｡
Should I take off your pants and underwear too?
I can do it myself.
(翔子)着替えを置いておきますね｡
I'll leave a change of clothes here.
翔子さん｡
何ですか？
Shouko-san.
What is it?
僕は 何もできませんでした｡
そんなことはないですよ｡
I couldn't do a thing.
That's not true.
咲太くんは よく頑張りました｡
You did very well.
翔子さんに何がわかるんですか｡
What would you even know about it?
かえでさんのために
もっとしてあげられたことが
You're thinking that maybe you could have done more for Kaede-san.
あったかもしれない｡
そんなふうに後悔している
I understand very well that that's your biggest regret right now.
咲太くんの気持ちならわかります｡
翔子さんは
何でもお見通しなんです｡
Your Shouko-san sees through everything!
かえでさんは 咲太くんのことを
恨んでましたか？
Did Kaede-san ever hold anything against you?
咲太くんのことが
ずっと好きでしたよね｡
She always showed you nothing but love, didn't she?
もっとできることが
あったかもしれない｡
I could've done more for her.
それは次の機会に
そうすればいいんですよ｡
Then do more next time.
かえでに次はないんですよ｡
Kaede doesn't have a next time.
咲太くんが そんな調子では
かえでさんがかわいそうですね｡
Given how you're acting,
I feel sorry for Kaede-san.
今度は 咲太くんが
後悔を残さないように
She tried so hard not to leave you
with regrets this time, but look at you.
頑張っていたのに｡
咲太くんが そばにいることが
自分の幸せなんだと
She tried to tell you in so many ways
that she was happy just having you by her side.
かえでさんは 一生懸命
伝えてくれていたじゃないですか｡
その思いが 咲太くんに
届いていないんじゃ
But you haven't gotten the message,
so I feel sorry for her.
かえでさんがかわいそうです｡
"November 5th. I'm keeping a diary, starting today.
｢11月５日 今日から
日記をつけることにしました｡
かえでの日記です｡
Kaede's diary.
名前は お兄ちゃんが
つけてくれました｡
Onii-chan gave me this name.
ﾉｰﾄとﾍﾟﾝも お兄ちゃんが
買ってくれたものです｡
He also bought me this pen and notebook.
かえでには お父さんとお母さんと
お兄ちゃんがいます｡
I have a father, a mother, and an older brother.
でも よくわかりません｡
But I don't know them.
かえでには記憶がないそうです｡
It seems I've lost my memories.
The doctors said it was amnesia
caused by a dissociative disorder.
解離性障害の記憶喪失だと
お医者さんは言っていました｡
難しいです｡
It's hard to understand.
I wasn't who I am until a short while ago.
少し前まで かえでは
かえでじゃなかったそうです｡
花楓さんが かえでだったんだと
教えてもらいました｣｡
I'm told that it was Kaede-san here, not me."
(かえで)｢でも かえでは
花楓さんを知りません｡
But I don't know Kaede-san.
会ったことがありません｡
I've never met her.
やっぱり難しいです｡
It really is hard to understand.
12月10日 なんだか お母さんと
お父さんがつらそうです｡
December 10th. Father and Mother
look like they're in pain.
Father was talking to the doctor for a long time.
お父さんは お医者さんと
ずっと話をしていました｡
いつ治るんですか？ と 何度も
お医者さんに聞いてました｡
He kept asking her, "When will she be cured?"
かえでは 病気なんでしょうか？
Am I... sick?
花楓さんの記憶が戻ったら
かえでは どうなるんでしょうか｡
What will happen to me when
Kaede-san's memories come back?
Where will I go?
かえでは どこに
行ってしまうんでしょうか｡
考えていたら 怖くなって
泣いてしまいました｡
Thinking about it scared me and made me cry.
３月７日 かえでは
引っ越すことになりました｡
March 7th. I'm going to be moving.
持っていきたいものは
かえでが選んでいいと
Onii-chan said I could pick
what I wanted to take with me.
お兄ちゃんが言ってくれました｡
I find it hard to look at the things
in Kaede-san's room.
花楓さんのお部屋にあるものは
ちょっと苦手です｡
本と本棚だけは
持っていくことにしました｡
I decided to take just the books and the bookshelf.
かえでさんの集めた本
いっぱいあります｡
Kaede-san's collected a lot of books!
なすのも一緒に引っ越しです｡
Oh, Nasuno's moving with us too.
新しいおうちに到着です｡
We've arrived at our new home!
いつか かえでが治ったら
One day, when I'm healed,
I think Kaede-san will come back.
花楓さんが
帰ってくるんだと思います｡
So in this new home,
だから かえでは
この新しい家で
Azusagawa Kaede
かえでをかえでにしてくれた
お兄ちゃんのために
Azusagawa Kaede
I'll try my hardest to be the best little sister
for Onii-chan, who let me be myself.
Azusagawa Kaede
立派な妹になれるよう
頑張ります｡
Azusagawa Kaede
お兄ちゃんは この春から
高校生です｡
Azusagawa Kaede
Onii-chan starts high school this spring!
峰ヶ原高校という学校に通います｡
He'll be going to a school called Minegahara High.
お兄ちゃんがｱﾙﾊﾞｲﾄを始めました｡
Onii-chan started a part-time job!
帰ってくるのが
とても遅くなります｡
He'll be coming home very late.
寂しいですけど
なすのと お留守番 頑張ります｡
It makes me feel lonely,
but I'll watch the house with Nasuno.
初めてのお給料で お兄ちゃんが
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞのDVDを買ってくれました｡
Onii-chan bought me a DVD about
pandas with his first paycheck!
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞはすてきです｡ 癒やされます｡
Pandas are wonderful!
They're so soothing!
なんと お兄ちゃんに
彼女ができました｡
Would you believe it?
Onii-chan got a girlfriend!
It can't be! But it's true!
ﾊﾞｶな… 本当なのです｡
麻衣さんは とてもいい人です｡
Mai-san is a really nice girl.
ﾃﾚﾋﾞにも出ている人気者です｡
I hear she's a popular actress who's all over TV.
８月２日 今日から
お兄ちゃんのお友達が
August 2nd.
One of Onii-chan's friends
is staying with us from today.
お泊まりします｡
双葉理央さんです｡
Her name is Futaba Rio.
９月20日 お兄ちゃんが
不良に目覚めました｡
September 20th.
I thought Onii-chan became a gigolo,
but I was wrong.
でも 違いました｡ のどかさんは
麻衣さんの妹でした｣｡
Nodoka-san is Mai-san's little sister!
(翔子)｢かえでにも
知っていることがあります｡
"There is something I've learned.
お兄ちゃんは ずっと
後悔しています｡
Onii-chan's been regretting it this whole time.
花楓さんがいじめられて
つらいときに
When Kaede-san was suffering from bullying,
助けてあげられなかったことを
後悔しています｡
he couldn't help her, and he regrets that.
かえでには わかります｡
I can tell.
もし このまま かえでが
いなくなったら
If nothing changes and I go away someday,
きっと お兄ちゃんは また
何もできなかったと
I'm sure Onii-chan will have regrets again,
thinking he couldn't do anything.
後悔すると思います｡
だから…｣｡
That's why..."
That's why I decided to make a list of goals.
(かえで)｢だから かえでは
目標を作ることにしました｡
お兄ちゃんと一緒に叶える
目標です｡
Goals to complete together with Onii-chan!
I don't want Onii-chan to have any regrets if I disappear.
かえでがいなくなっても
かえでは お兄ちゃんに
後悔してほしくありません｡
かえでの夢を
いっぱい叶えてあげたって
I want him to hold his head high and say
he made lots of my dreams come true.
胸を張ってほしいんです｡
悲しい記憶よりも
楽しくて うれしくて
Rather than painful memories,
I want to leave loads of fun and happy memories
that make him smile before I go.
笑顔になれる記憶を
いっぱい残していきたいと
思います｡
I'd be glad if he could remember me
with a smile after I'm gone.
かえでがいなくなっても
お兄ちゃんには
かえでのことを笑いながら
思い出してもらえたら
うれしいです｡ そのために
かえでは頑張ります｡
I'll do my best to make sure he does!
たぶん かえでに残された時間は
そんなにないんだと思います｡
I probably don't have too much time left.
お願いします もう少しだけ
かえでに時間をください｡
Please, give me a little more time.
お兄ちゃんのおかげで かえでは
たくさんの丸をつけられました｡
Thanks to Onii-chan,
I got to mark lots of my goals complete!
ずっと怖かった外にも
出られるようになりました｡
I was so scared of going outside,
but I managed to do it.
花丸です｡
I'm on a hot streak!
I went to hang out at Mai-san's place,
麻衣さんのおうちにも
遊びに行けました｡
電車にも乗れました｡
took the train,
played at the beach,
海でも遊びました｡
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞも見られました｡
and saw the pandas too.
And while I cheated a little,
ちょっとｽﾞﾙですけど
学校にも行けました｡
I even made it to school.
全部 お兄ちゃんのおかげです｡
It's all thanks to Onii-chan.
お兄ちゃんが かえでに
いっぱいの幸せをくれました｡
He's brought so much joy into my life.
お兄ちゃんの妹になれて
かえでは幸せです｡
I'm so happy I got to be his little sister.
今も 今までも これからも
大好きです｡
Then, now, and forever... I'll always love him!
明日は お昼の学校に行きます｣｡
Tomorrow, I'll go to school during the day.
(翔子)我慢しなくていいんですよ｡
You don't have to hold it in.
I can't cry!
僕は泣いたらﾀﾞﾒなんですよ！
ここで泣いたら 僕は
かえでの思いを裏切ることになる｡
If I do, I'll be betraying Kaede's hopes.
かえでが頑張ってくれたのに
She tried so hard!
それを僕が台なしにして
どうするんですか！
How could I make all her efforts go to waste?!
その悲しみも かえでさんが
咲太くんにくれた
The sorrow you're feeling is an important part
of what Kaede-san has left you.
大切なものなんですから｡
かえでさんの存在の大きさ
そのものなんですから｡
It shows how big of a place she holds in your heart.
咲太くんは お兄ちゃんなんだから
全部受け止めてあげなさい｡
You're her Onii-chan,
so you should accept it all.
November 28th
It looks like you'll be all right,
so your Shouko-san will be on her way.
ひでえ顔｡
Wow, I look like death.
[ﾃｰﾌ]１件のﾒｯｾｰｼﾞがあります｡
You have one new message.
Sakurajima Mai
[ﾃｰﾌ]11月27日 午後10時５分｡
November 27, 10:05 PM.
[ﾃｰﾌ]私だけど
かえでちゃんは学校に行けた？
It's me. Did Kaede-chan make it to school?
[ﾃｰﾌ]遅くなってもいいから
電話ちょうだい｡
Doesn't matter how late it is. Call me back.
Sakuta
咲太？
[℡]おはようございます 麻衣さん｡
Sakuta?
Good morning, Mai-san.
[℡]昨日は すみません｡
Sorry about last night.
[℡]いろいろあって
眠ってしまったみたいで
There was a lot happening, and I didn't
notice your message before I fell asleep.
[℡]電話に気づきませんでした｡
いいのよ 別に｡
It's fine.
それより かえでちゃんは？
How'd it go with Kaede-chan?
お昼の学校には行けた？
[℡]いえ 学校へは
Did she make it to school during the day?
No, she couldn't go to school.
行けませんでした｡
今は病院にいます｡
She's in the hospital now.
[℡]昔の記憶が戻ったんです｡
Her old memories have returned.
It's just... She doesn't remember
anything about these last two years.
[℡]ただ この２年間のことは
何も覚えてないみたいです｡
[℡]麻衣さんのことも
また改めて紹介しないと
Looks like I'll have to introduce you all over again.
ﾀﾞﾒみたいです｡
咲太…｡
Sakuta...
Oh, but don't worry.
あ～ でも 心配はいりません｡
体のほうは元気ですし
She's physically fine,
病院といっても 検査と
様子見のための入院なので｡
and she's only in the hospital
for scans and monitoring.
[℡]咲太のほうは大丈夫なの？
But are you okay?
僕も 昨日はちょっと
混乱しましたけど
I was a bit of a mess yesterday,
[℡]今朝は もう だいぶ
落ち着きましたから｡
(ﾉｯｸ)
but I've calmed down now.
≪麻衣さん
準備はできましたか？
Mai-san, are you ready?
ごめん 迎えが来たみたい｡
もう行かないと｡
Sorry, I have to go.
My manager's here to pick me up.
[℡]はい それじゃ
また夜にゆっくりと｡
Sure. Let's chat more at night.
[℡]撮影 頑張ってください｡
うん それじゃ｡
Good luck with the shoot.
Thanks.
Bye.
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
Fujisawa General Hospital
What happened yesterday?
昨日 どうしたの？
ﾄｲﾚに行ったっきりで
You said you were going to the toilet
and never came back.
戻ってこないんだもん｡
すげえ下痢して
I had so much diarrhea that I ended up
forming a lifelong bond with the can.
ﾄｲﾚと親友になってたんだよ｡
もう汚いな｡
Dude, that's gross.
それより花楓 ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞ好きか？
That aside, Kaede, do you like pandas?
急に何？
好きか？
Where'd that come from?
Do you?
嫌いじゃないよ｡
じゃ 退院したら見に行くぞ｡
I don't dislike them.
Let's go see them once you're discharged, then.
いいけど…
わけわかんないよ｡
Okay, but I don't understand why.
僕が見たいんだよ
つきあってくれ｡
I want to see them.
Give me some company.
そういうの 妹じゃなくて
彼女をつくって
Instead of asking your little sister,
shouldn't you get a girlfriend
and go see them on a date?
ﾃﾞｰﾄで行くべきなんじゃないの？
彼女ならいるぞ｡
I do have a girlfriend, actually.
ｳｿ!?
今度 紹介するから
No way!
I'll introduce you sometime. Be ready.
覚悟しとけよ｡
はい ｵｯｹｰです｡
はい 本番いきます！
Rolling take one!
本番！
Take one!
Blossoming
Future
大丈夫ですか？
え？
Are you all right?
彼氏と何かあったのかと｡
Did something happen with your boyfriend?
大丈夫です｡
I'm fine.
《結局 翔子さんは
あれきり僕の前から
Shouko-san hasn't shown her face to me since then.
姿を消してしまった｡
Makinohara Shouko
Calling
中学生のほうの
牧之原さんとの電話は
I haven't been able to get through to the
middle-schooler Makinohara-san, either.
つながらないし
翔子さんの存在って
Just what was Shouko-san in the end?
結局 何だったんだろう…》
(理央)最初から 年上の
牧之原翔子なんて人間は
Maybe the older Makinohara Shouko
never existed in the first place.
存在してなかったんじゃない？
いや さすがに それはないだろう｡
Nah, that's out of the question.
だけど 実際 ２年前と今回
牧之原翔子の姿を見たのは
But be it two years ago or now,
you're the only one who's ever seen her, right?
梓川だけなんでしょ？
他の誰にも観測はされてない｡
Nobody else has observed her.
また観測の話か｡
Not the observation crap again.
Or we could go with the simple explanation
あるいは もっとｼﾝﾌﾟﾙに考えて
梓川の作り上げた ただの幻
and say she's an illusion you conjured up—
ﾌﾞﾀ野郎の妄想とかね｡
the delusions of a teenage pig.
December 1st
これも妄想？
Is this a delusion too?
映画の撮影 終わったんですか？
今日の分はね｡
Did the film shoot finish?
For today, yes.
明日の朝いちばんの新幹線で
また金沢に戻るから｡
I'm taking the first shinkansen
back to Kanazawa in the morning.
あ…｡
なによ うれしくないの？
What? Not happy to see me?
めちゃくちゃうれしいに
決まってるじゃないですか｡
I'm over the moon, obviously!
あっ お茶淹れますね｡
お茶は 私が淹れるから
Oh, I'll make some tea.
I'll handle the tea. You go get dressed.
先に服を着なさい｡
You'll catch a cold.
風邪ひくわよ｡
はい｡
Okay.
でも ﾎﾝﾄにびっくりしたな｡
But man, you really surprised me.
帰ってくるなら 一言
連絡もらえれば…｡
If you were coming back,
you could've called and let me know...
ちょっ 麻衣さん!?
Hey...
Mai-san?!
これ どういうこと？
それはですね その…｡
What's this all about?
U-Uh, well, you see...
かえでの記憶が戻った日
翔子さんが 突然現れたんです｡
The day Kaede regained her memories,
Shouko-san showed up out of nowhere.
それで うちに来てくれて
She came over and consoled me when I was down in the dumps.
落ち込んでた僕を
元気づけてくれて…｡
その手紙は 次の朝起きたら
残ってたんです｡
I found that note when I woke up the next morning.
あっ といっても 翔子さんが
But it's not like she stayed over or anything.
うちに
泊まってったわけじゃなくて…｡
Actually, I fell asleep before I knew it,
いや 僕は 知らない間に
寝ちゃってたので
so I don't know when she left...
翔子さんが いつ帰ったのかも
わからなかったわけですが…｡
でも 違うんです
安心してください｡
But it's not like that!
Don't worry. We didn't do anything.
決して やましいことは…｡
あの夜 ﾎﾝﾄに僕
泣き疲れて眠ってしまって…｡
That night, I honestly cried myself to sleep.
もういい｡
Forget it.
咲太が大丈夫なら それでいい｡
麻衣さん…｡
If you're fine, that's all I need.
Mai-san!
でも ごめん
今日はやっぱり帰る｡
But I'm sorry. I'll have to go back tonight.
Wait, go back?!
えっ ちょっ 帰るって…｡
金沢｡
To Kanazawa.
新幹線 まだあるから｡
The shinkansen's still running.
Wait, Mai-san!
待ってください 麻衣さん！
麻衣さん…｡
Mai-san?
しばらく そういうの無理だから｡
I can't. Not for a while.
ごめん 麻衣さん…｡
Sorry, Mai-san.
そんなこと言われるために
I'm not dating you to hear those words.
私は咲太と
つきあってるんじゃない｡
December 2nd
What's wrong, Sakuta? Your eyes look dead.
(国見)どうした？ 咲太
目が死んでるぞ｡
(朋絵)いつもと
同じじゃないですか｡
But they always do.
Nah, they're deader than usual today.
いや 今日は 特に死んでるな｡
先輩 体調が悪いんなら
帰ったほうがいいんじゃない？
Senpai, if you're not feeling well,
maybe just go home?
いや 大丈夫｡
Nah, I'm good.
Welcome...
いらっしゃいませ…｡
(落下音)
いや～ 先輩 何しようと！
Senpai! What're ya doin'?!
なんだよ 待ち伏せか？
What's this? An ambush?
(のどか)ちょっと
話があるんだけど｡
We need to talk.
今度にしてくれ｡ 腹減ったし
Some other time, please.
I'm starving, and I've got a lot to think about.
いろいろ
考えなきゃいけないことも
あるんだ｡
咲太は お姉ちゃんのことだけ
You don't need to think about
anything but Onee-chan.
考えてろ｡
だから いろいろってのは
It is all about her.
麻衣さんのことだって｡
お姉ちゃん 無理して
She came back from Kanazawa
when she really shouldn't have, y'know.
金沢から帰ってきたのに｡
だから あれは麻衣さんが
But she got the wrong idea about Shouko-san—
翔子さんのことを勘違いして…｡
はぁ？
Huh? Do you seriously believe that?
本気で そんなこと思ってんの？
Chill. She knows she can trust you.
お姉ちゃん 咲太のことは
ちゃんと信用してる｡
だったら…｡
咲太のことが心配で
Then why?
She came back out of concern for you.
帰ってきたんだよ｡ ここ最近
You've had your hands full
with Kaede-chan lately,
咲太は ずっと
かえでちゃんのことで
大変だったから｡
少しでもそばにいて
so she was hoping to be with you
and cheer you up a little.
元気づけてあげようと
思ってたんだよ？
しかも 今日は
お姉ちゃんの誕生日だったのに｡
And today was her birthday, too.
誕生日？
ほら 12月２日！
Birthday?
See? December 2nd!
てか なんで
彼女の誕生日も知らないのよ！
Wait, why don't you know your girlfriend's birthday?
豊浜 ｽﾏﾎ貸してくれ｡
はぁ？
Toyohama, gimme your phone.
What? She's still in the middle of her shoot.
お姉ちゃん 今日はまだﾛｹ中だよ｡
いいから貸してくれ｡
Just gimme that.
何やってんの？
まだ間に合う｡
What are you doing?
I can still make it...
大宮まで出て 新幹線使えば｡
if I rush to Omiya and take the shinkansen from there.
本気!?
もちろん｡
You serious?
Extremely.
向こうに着いたら電話して！
Call me once you get there!
それとなく お姉ちゃんに
居場所聞いといてあげる！
I'll casually ask Onee-chan where she is!
どうして咲太がいるのよ？
Why are you here?
のどかが しつこく
連絡してきたから
Nodoka kept buzzing me nonstop,
so I had a feeling I'd be seeing you.
もしかしてって思ったの｡
それとなくって言ってたのに｡
What happened to asking casually?
ここまで来るのに
お金かかったでしょ？
It must've cost a lot to get here.
まあ ちょっと…｡
帰りの電車賃は？
Yeah, kinda.
Do you have money for the trip back?
新幹線に乗らなければ帰れるかな｡
ﾊｧ…｡
If I don't take the shinkansen, maybe.
涼子さん 本当に
申し訳ないんですけど
Ryouko-san, I feel terrible for asking,
ｽﾀｯﾌさんが泊まってるﾎﾃﾙに
空きがないか
but can you see if there are any vacancies
in the hotel the crew are staying at?
調べてもらっていいですか？
確認しておきます｡
I'll check.
And?
それで？
えっと…｡
Uh...
とりあえず 誕生日
おめでとうございます｡
For starters, happy birthday.
言うのが遅い｡
Took you long enough.
ﾃﾞｰﾄは15分だけですからね｡
Keep your date to fifteen minutes, okay?
それと ちゃんと 彼氏に
元気もらっておいてください｡
Also, make sure to have
your boyfriend cheer you up.
ちょ ちょっと涼子さん
ﾍﾝなこと言わないでください｡
H-Hey, Ryouko-san! Don't be weird!
なにﾆﾔﾆﾔしてるのよ
ほら 行くわよ｡
What are you grinning for?
Let's go.
麻衣さん 元気なかったんだ｡
咲太は ずいぶん元気そうね｡
So you needed cheering up, huh?
Meanwhile, you seem to be awfully cheery yourself.
僕も今日は 一日
しょんぼりしてましたって｡
Hardly. I spent all day down in the dumps.
それより寒いんだけど｡
Forget that. I'm freezing here.
しばらく こういうの無理って
言ってましたよね？
Didn't you say you couldn't for a while?
寒いからいいの｡
冬万歳｡
I'm too cold to care.
Long live winter.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
あっ 本当にすみませんでした｡
いいのよ もう｡
It's fine, really.
No, it's not. Let me apologize.
よくないです
ちゃんと謝らせてください｡
麻衣さん せっかく
僕のこと心配して
I deserve to, after you rushed home
all the way just for me.
金沢から駆けつけてくれたのに｡
私も ちゃんと謝らなきゃね｡
I need to apologize too.
せっかく 咲太が
会いにきてくれたんだから
You came all the way to see me,
so I should be upfront.
素直にならないと｡
咲太に誰かの支えが
必要だったのは
I knew that you'd needed someone
to be there for you.
ちゃんとわかってた｡
I was just hurt that it wasn't me.
それが私じゃなかったのが
ちょっとｼｮｯｸだったの｡
だから 昨日… じゃなくて
もう おとといだったわね｡
That's why, yesterday—
or the day before yesterday now, I guess—
あんなこと
言っちゃったんだと思う｡
I went and said that.
咲太…｡
ん？
Sakuta.
咲太がいちばん大変なときに
一緒にいてあげられなくて
I'm so sorry I couldn't be there for you
when you needed me most.
ごめんね｡
麻衣さんは いるだけで
But your very existence
makes me happy every day.
いつも僕を
幸せな気分にしてくれますよ｡
Hey, you're saying it's not because of anything I'm doing.
それ 私は何もしてないじゃない｡
でも それって すごいことだと
思うけどな｡
But I believe that's incredible in its own right.
僕も 麻衣さんの
そういう存在になりたいし｡
And I want to be that person for you.
咲太…｡
何ですか？
Sakuta.
What?
Close your eyes.
目 とじなさい｡
ん？
咲太…｡
Sakuta...
ｲﾀﾀﾀ… 痛いって 麻衣さん！
Ow, ow, ow! That hurts, Mai-san!
てか なんで!?
だって
Why, even?!
I mean...
咲太にとって これが
いちばんのご褒美でしょ？
Isn't this what you enjoy most?
katarenai nemurenai traumerei
I can't talk about it or sleep, so I daydream
anata no miteru shoutai
These are my true colors, as you see
dare mo yomenai karte
Nobody can read my medical chart
fukashigi shiritai dake
So puzzling, I just want to know what it means
kyou mo hitorigoto
I mumble to myself again today
nani mo muri wo shinai de
Feeling too lazy to push myself
aisaretai
I want to be loved for free
owaranai koto wa nai traumerei
Dreaming a never-ending daydream
anata to matagu kyoukai
I cross the border with you at my side
dare mo yomenai karte
Nobody can read my medical chart
fukashigi shiritai dake
So puzzling, I just want to know what it means
Azusagawa Kaede
Hey...
あのね…｡
ん？
ありがとう お兄ちゃん｡
Thanks, Onii-chan.
ああ 僕のほうこそ
ありがとう｡
Sure.
And thank you too.
なんで ありがとうって言うの？
Why are you thanking me?
そういや 鹿野さんが
遊びに来たいって言ってたけど
Oh yeah, Kano-san says she wants to
come hang out. What do you wanna do?
どうする？
こみちゃんが？
Komi-chan?
Yeah.
会いたい…｡
じゃあ そう伝えておく｡
I wanna see her.
I'll let her know, then.
他にしたいことある？
ん～とね…｡
Anything else you wanna do?
Well...
学校に行きたい｡
行けるようになりたい｡
I wanna go to school.
I wanna be able to go.
もう怖くないのか？
大丈夫だと思う｡
Not scared anymore?
I'll be fine, I think.
だって…｡
ん？
After all...
私は ひとりじゃないもん｡
I'm not in this alone.
行くか｡
うん｡
Shall we go?
Yep.
That's so me.
さすが僕 ﾌﾞﾀ野郎だな｡
A total pig.
Thank  you  for  watching